#### Senior Software Developer

Amsterdam, Netherlands

tim.zhlobich@gmail.com

GitHub

LinkedIn

# **Experience highlights**

10 years of Scala/Java/full-stack product development

### Shell Recharge (former NewMotion), Settlement

Shell EV Charging Solutions, Amsterdam, Netherlands, Sep 2021 - present

Shell Recharge provides everything from charging stations to mobile apps for drivers

- · development & support of settlement/subscriptions/tariffs domain (backend services)
- Scrum master

Scala, Akka, Cats, Kafka, Postgres, k8s, AWS

#### **Evolution Gaming, Dice**

Evolution Gaming, Minsk, Belarus, Sep 2019 - Aug 2021

Evolution Gaming is the world leader in live casino providers market.

• development & support of Dice and Deal/No Deal games suites

Scala, Akka Persistence, Cats, Monix, Kafka, Cassandra, k8s

#### Adform (Integrated Advertising Platform), Site Tracking

Adform, Minsk, Belarus, Aug 2017 - Jun 2019

Advertising platform provider.

- management tools of user activity tracking
- · end-to-end domain REST & GraphQL services development
- · architecture and release planning
- performance analysis

Scala, C#, Java, SQL, MongoDB, Akka, Slick, ASP .NET Core, docker, k8s, JMC

#### **Project Falcon**

Kronos Inc. / Epam Systems, Minsk, Belarus, Sep 2016 - Aug 2017

- · SaaS tenant management system
- domain REST service development
- tests

Java, Spring Boot, Postgres, Jenkins

#### **ASCET IDE**

ETAS / Epam Systems, Minsk, Belarus, Dec 2015 - Jul 2016

- Eclipse-based IDE for automotive industry
- UI development

- providing support for custom language model
- tests

Java, SWT, Eclipse RCP, EMF, XText

#### Kyriba SaaS

Kyriba Corp. / Belhard Development, Minsk, Belarus, Sep 2012 - Nov 2015

- · proactive treasury management platform
- top 3 contributor
- full stack dev
  - o requirement analysis, planning
  - DB maintenance
  - business logic
  - o UI
  - tests
- support level 3
  - o customer case investigations
  - o code & performance analysis
  - log analysis
  - o development of log processing tools
- G1 migration team
  - o benchmark development
  - o gathering statistics and comparing JVM garbage collectors
  - analyzing G1 weak spots
  - preparing migration procedure
- organization of a series of internal workshops on ML, distributed systems, text indexing, Scala, Java compilation process

Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Scala, Java EE, Swing, Guava, EclipseLink, JBoss, JUnit, Mockito, JConsole, JVisualVM, GCViewer

#### wartremover

open source project, May 2016 - present

- Flexible Scala code linting tool (compiler plugin + sbt plugin)
- · top 3 contributor
- collaborator

Scala, scalac

## Education

no bachelor's degree

#### **Belarusian State University**

Applied Mathematics, 2007 - 2010

some university courses

#### Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

Computer Science, 2011 - 2012

some university courses